Ashish Surana

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONTEND)

C Phone: (+91) 9784878727 | ☐ Email: ashishsurana.in@gmail.com | ★ ashishsurana.in | O ashishsurana | in ashishsurana

Summary _____

Creative and self-starting software engineer with 8+ years of experience in Front-end Engineering. I've worked across B2C and B2B products with focus on performance and business KPIs. The challenges of scaling and improving UX is my motivation. I am always driven to write clean, composable & testable code.

Skills _____

Proficiency JavaScript, Functional programming

Libraries - React, Redux, Jest

Frameworks - Express, Node.js, Next.js

Typed Systems - Typescript

Also Familiar with GraphQL, AWS, Apollo, Unit Testing

Packaging - webpack, Docker **Automation** - Gitlab CI

Release Management - npm & Semver, A/B Testing

Certifications Red Hat Certified Engineer (**RHCE**)

Experience _____

Level AI Noida, India

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONTEND)

Sept. 2023 - Present

- About Level AI Level AI is a startup that is building a platform for AI-powered customer service. And my roles were as follows:
- Ownership of Front end part of Analytics Module of product. Responsibilities includes **tackling tech-debt, phased releases, UX Detailings**
- Responsible for the initial setup of the frontend, **Design System, Test suite** and some low level system utilities.
- Contributed in improving **Engineering processes** and Automation using **AI Tools** and Gitlab CI.
- Actively involved in recruitment, knowledge sharing, improving processes and onboarding new joiners along with cross team coordinations.
- Technologies React, A/B Testing, Firebase, Data Visualisations, Jest

Trivago N V Düsseldorf, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (JAVASCRIPT)

Nov. 2020 - Aug. 2022

- About trivago trivago is a global hotel search platform. The Product consist of a meta search and a booking engine. And my roles were as follows:
- Ownership of Front end part of express-booking, Responsibilities including preparing **design documents, tackling tech-debt, improving processes**
- Actively involved in cross team communication with Designers, Product owners, Engineers to take the product forward with matching business KPIs.
- Technologies React, symphony, Server Side Rendering, A/B Testing

Innovaccer Analytics Noida, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - I

Jan. 2018 - Nov. 2020

- About Innovaccer Innovaccer is a **healthcare** data activation platform for care management. The Product consist of a Micro Front-end application and my roles were as follows:
- Ownership of development and releasing two modules in React using Redux and styled components
- Technologies React, AngularJs, Next.js, Express, Server Side Rendering

AadhaarApi.com Pune, India

JAVASCRIPT ENGINEER

Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- About AdhaarAPI Aadhaar is the database containing biometrics 1.3 Billion Indians and AadhaarAPI is a product to leverage the power by developing SDKs over it. I worked on the back-end for the "Know Your Customer (EKYC)" using Aadhaar APIs
- Successfully delivered Dashboard from scratch and developed efficient REST APIs for improving workflows
- Technologies React, Redux, Server Side Rendering, Node.js, Postgres, AWS

Education _

Rajasthan Technical University

Kota, India

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING)

June 2017

Awards & Participations _

Star Performer, Peer recognition Awards

Level AI, Noida

DECEMBER, 2024

• Won star performer award and few peer recognitions for collaborations.

Hackathon Winner trivago, Germany

MARCH, 2022

• Won the internal Hackathon in which Challenge was to simplify the UI when user is booking a room. Later it was accepted as well after A/B Test.